Adrian Contursi-Reynoso

Santa Fe, Santa Fe, Argentina



acontursi@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/acontursi

Summary

I am a Political and Data Scientist who is passionate about the academic goal to pursue new knowledge. Because of that, I combine Political and Data Analysis with Computing. This allows me to build a strong background in Statistic and Geographic Information Systems.

I have a demonstrated history of more than 15 years of leading projects in the Public Sector, and more than 7 years in the Academic sector, teaching and researching.

I have also been working as Consultant for international organizations which offer me the possibility to grow my skills in Collaboration, Adaptability, Negotiation, Solve problem and Leading.

I am currently seeking new challenges and opportunities, so if you would like to work together, contact me.

Experience



Associate Professor of Applied Statistics

Universidad Autónoma de Entre Ríos Mar 2022 - Present (11 months)



Associate Professor at Social Research

Universidad Autónoma de Entre Ríos Jun 2020 - Present (2 years 8 months)

Associate Professor at Political Geography

Universidad Autónoma de Entre Ríos May 2019 - Present (3 years 9 months)

Associate Professor at Geography of the Capitalist Globalization of the Nation **States**

Universidad Autónoma de Entre Ríos Apr 2017 - Present (5 years 10 months)



Assistant Professor at Political Geography and Electoral Geography

Universidad Nacional del Litoral Jun 2016 - Present (6 years 8 months)



Chief of Division.

Gobierno de la Provincia de Santa Fe

Independent Consultant

Organización de los Estados Americanos

Apr 2022 - Dec 2022 (9 months)

Network Studies for the Reduction of Polarization and Conflict.

Based on the selection of eight Latin American countries, a study was carried out on the impact of affective polarization on Social Networks.

An algorithm was created that made it possible to measure, together with the visualization and analysis of social networks, the evolution of polarization at the national level. As well as identifying relevant issues and actors that could contribute to reducing the existing polarization.

Independent Consultant

Organización de los Estados Americanos

May 2022 - Aug 2022 (4 months)

Support for the consolidation of the Democracy Observatory.

Contribute to the preparation of the document on Democracy in the Americas.

Chapter 2: Democracy Observatory: indicators on the political, economic and social impact of the pandemic.

* It was supported in the elaboration and calculations of the indicators and indices of the chapter.

Chapter 3: Trends that may affect the effective exercise of democracy.

* The sections on "Political polarization, political fanaticism, hate speech and its effects on governance" and "Viral democracy, social networks, disinformation and fake news" were developed.

🖳 External Consultant

Organización de los Estados Americanos

Dec 2018 - Jan 2019 (2 months)

Political and Social Network Analysis.

Head of Technical Division.

Gobierno de la Provincia de Santa Fe

Feb 2013 - Sep 2018 (5 years 8 months)

I am responsible for the development of the SiGI (Integral Management System) for the General Direction of Programming at DPV. This include internal coordination and coordination with other divisions and governmental organism.

I work together with the Planning Direction to upgrade the Vial Inventory, we georeference trace and objects to update it. This include data collection in fieldwork and post process to obtain geographical objects compatible with international norms and standards (ISO 19100, 19115, 19139 e ISO/TC 211).

I am the nexus between the DPV and other governmental organism. I represent the DPV in front of the National Comission of Spatial Activities, where I advise to acquire products from satellite images. Also, I am part of a special commission between the DPV and the Cadastre Service and Land Information, where we update the geographic information which affect physical, legal and economically the properties in the province.

Intern

Organización de los Estados Americanos

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017 (4 months)

To contribute to the development of methodologies for the quantitative analysis of data extracted from the monitoring of open sources of information, building on the basis of the OAS Americas Digital Information System (ADIS)

Implement at least one social network monitoring and analysis pilot in electoral context (Ecuador / Honduras MOE).

Collaborate with knowledge management for situational analysis, design and construction of databases and compilation of relevant documents (eSAPEM).

Support political analysis efforts, providing inputs for briefings in response to emerging needs. Document methodological contributions, providing to institutional memory and the sustainability of political analysis efforts.

Credit Teacher

Concordia Language Villages Jun 2013 - Jul 2013 (2 months)

Programmer.

Gobierno de la Provincia de Santa Fe Sep 2005 - Jan 2013 (7 years 5 months)

Teacher at Middlebury-Monterey Language Academy

Middlebury College
Jun 2011 - Jul 2011 (2 months)
MMLA at Roger Williams University

Teacher at Middlebury-Monterey Language Academy

Middlebury College Jun 2010 - Jul 2010 (2 months) MMLA at Bard College at Simon's Rock

Credit Teacher

Concordia Language Villages Jun 2006 - Jul 2006 (2 months) ELdB at Wilder Foundation

Credit Teacher

Concordia Language Villages Jun 2005 - Aug 2005 (3 months) ELdB at Wilder Foundation



Concordia Language Villages

Jun 2004 - Aug 2004 (3 months) ELdB at Wilder Foundation

Senior Counselor

Concordia Language Villages Jun 2003 - Jul 2003 (2 months) ELdB at Oak Hills

Education

Universidad Nacional de Rosario

Master's Degree, Integration and International Cooperation 2014 - 2016

University of Oxford

Annenberg-Oxford Media Policy Summer Institute, Communication and Media Studies 2018 - 2018

Universidad Abierta Interamericana

Associate's Degree, International Relations and Affairs 2014 - 2014

universidad Nacional del Litoral

Bachelor's Degree, Political Science 2008 - 2014

Instituto Superior "César Vázquez"

Prof., Education 2000 - 2005

Skills

Data Science • Data Analysis • Research • University Teaching • Statistics • Writing • R (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) • Data Mining • Machine Learning